A Finding Aid to the Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney Papers, 1851-1975, bulk 1888-1942, in the Archives of American Art AAA.whitgert
Archives of American Art
- Philanthropy Files, bulk 1915-1920; 1902-1923; Series 6; 2 Linear feet Boxes 15-17
  - Charities and War Appeals (Box 15)
    - U, 1917-1920 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - V, 1917-1920 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - W, 1915-1920 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
    - Y, 1917-1920 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1915-1920 (Box 16, Folder 10-14)
    - Lists, 1917-1919 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Greenwich House, 1902-1920 (Box 16, Folder 16-20)
  - Juilly Hospital (Box 16)
    - Annual Report, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Book of Patient Stories and Photographs, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Certificate of Service, circa 1918 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
      - Chronological, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Chronological, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 25-27)
      - Chronological, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 28-31)
      - Chronological, (Copies of Letters to Mother from Alden?), 1916 (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - Chronological, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 33-34)
      - Chronological, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - Chronological, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Chronological, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - Chronological, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Lists, undated (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Photograph Album, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 1923; undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, Snapshots, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Postcards, 1916-1917 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material, 1916-1917 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Writings, 1974; 1889-1942; Series 7; 10 Linear feet Boxes 17-26
  This series consists of extensive drafts, handwritten and typed manuscripts, and various copies of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney's writings, which include novels, plays, stories, as well as some autobiographical and early writings, notes and writings on art, and published writings. As a whole, these writings document what was an important means of creative expression for Whitney, one which she pursued from her earliest childhood until her death, and what was her principle creative activity in the last years of her life.
  7.1: Novels, circa 1901-1931
  7.2: Plays, circa 1933-1942
  7.3: Stories, circa 1910-1942, 1974
  7.4: Journals and Notebooks, circa 1901-1940
  7.5: Unidentified Drafts and Fragments, 1910-1930s
  7.6: Other Writings, 1889-1940
  7.7: Writings by Others, circa 1918
  Writings are typically arranged in alphabetical order according to title and are arranged as seven subseries.
  Writings are partially scanned; duplicates and extensive edited versions of manuscripts have not been scanned.
  - Novels, circa 1901-1931; 7.1
    This subseries consists of drafts, manuscripts, and fragments of various novels written by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, one of which - Walking the Dusk - was published under the pseudonym L. J. Webb in 1932. The bulk of the subseries consists of early drafts of an untitled novel that begins "The Maison Feodor was..." Also included is a novel written under the pseudonym Phyllis Lane.
    Some related material may be found amongst the unidentified drafts and fragments subseries.
    Novels are partially scanned; duplicates and some draft versions have not been scanned.
    - As Seen Through a Glass Darkly, Drafts, 1902 (Box 17)
      - Notes and Outlines, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Chapters 1-4, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Chapters 5-6, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Chapters 7-8, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Chapters 9-10, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Chapters 11-12, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Chapters 13-14, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Chapter 16, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Chapters 17-18, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Chapters 19-20, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Chapter 21, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Chapters 25-26, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Chapters 27-28, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Chapters 29-30, circa 1902 (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
    - As Through a Glass Darkly (incomplete), undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Diana Opens the Door by Phyllis Lane (pseudonym of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney), circa 1931 (Box 17, Folder 22-24)
    - Drafts and Fragments, Miscellaneous, circa 1900 (Box 17, Folder 25-28)
    - Drafts and Fragments, Miscellaneous, circa 1900 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Maude - A Novel, circa 1901 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Their Emancipation - A Novel, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Manuscripts, undated (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
    - Untitled ("The Maison Feodor was...") (Box 18)
      - Manuscript, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Manuscript, Chapters 6-9, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Manuscript, Chapters 10-13, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Manuscript, Chapters 14-16, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Manuscript, Chapters 17-20, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Manuscript, Chapters 21-15, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Draft (Box 18)
        - Chapters 1-4, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
        - Chapters 5-14, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
        - Chapters 15-20, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
        - Chapters 21-25, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Early Drafts (Box 18)
        - Chapter 1, undated (Box 18, Folder 18-20)
        - Chapter 2, undated (Box 18, Folder 21-22)
        - Chapter 3, undated (Box 18, Folder 23-24)
        - Chapter 4, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
        - Chapter 5, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Chapter 6, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Chapter 7, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - Chapter 8, undated (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
        - Chapter 9, undated (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
        - Chapter 10, undated (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
        - Chapter 11, undated (Box 19, Folder 10-12)
        - Chapter 12, undated (Box 19, Folder 13-14)
        - Chapter 13, undated (Box 19, Folder 15-16)
        - Chapter 14, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
        - Chapter 15, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
        - Chapter 16, undated (Box 19, Folder 19-22)
        - Chapter 17, undated (Box 19, Folder 23-24)
        - Chapter 18, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
        - Chapter 19, undated (Box 19, Folder 26-27)
        - Chapter 20, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Chapter 21, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Chapter 22, undated (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
        - Chapter 23, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Chapter 24, undated (Box 20, Folder 6-7)
        - Chapter 25, undated (Box 20, Folder 8-10)
        - Chapter 26, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20, Folder 12-13)
    - Walking the Dusk (Box 20)
      - Drafts (Box 20)
        - Chapters 1-4, circa 1931 (Box 20, Folder 14)
        - Chapters 5-16, circa 1931 (Box 20, Folder 15-16)
        - Chapters 5-20, circa 1931 (Box 20, Folder 17-18)
        - Chapters 21-32, circa 1931 (Box 20, Folder 19-21)
        - Miscellaneous, circa 1931 (Box 20, Folder 22-24)
      - Proofs, circa 1931 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - The Wedge of Light (Box 20)
      - Draft, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - Outline and Notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - White Voices, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Plays, 1933-1942; 7.2
    This subseries consists of drafts and manuscripts of various plays written by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney. The most notable of these is The Hand, which began as a story (also called "The Scar" and "The Usurper") in the early 1930s; she first attempted to make the story into a play in the mid-1930s and eventually collaborated with Ronald Bodley on it beginning in 1941. Also included is one which may or may not have been written by Whitney, which is noted in the title of the folder in the list below.
    Plays are partially scanned; drafts and copies of typed manuscripts have not been scanned.
    - The Amazing Adventure of Mathilda Brown (by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney?), Synopsis, undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - The Hand (Box 20)
      - Early Versions of Story, circa 1933 (Box 20, Folder 30-32)
      - Act I, circa 1941 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
      - Act II, circa 1941 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Act III, circa 1941 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Critique, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Early Drafts, circa 1933-1942 (Box 21, Folder 6-9)
      - Drafts and Copies of Typed Manuscripts, circa 1933-1942 (Box 21, Folder 10-24)
      - Drafts and Copies of Typed Manuscripts, circa 1933-1942 (Box 22, Folder 1-13)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Untitled, Act II, circa 1934 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Stories, 1974; circa 1910-1942; 7.3
    This subseries consists of drafts and manuscripts of stories by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, many of which were written as part of a professional writing course at Columbia University taught by Helen Hull in the early-1940s and including one written under the pseudonym Phyllis Lane. Also found are critiques by Hull of some of the stories, and certain stories that may or may not have been written by Whitney, which are noted in the title of the folders in the list below.
    Stories are partially scanned; duplicates and some draft versions have not been scanned.
    - "The Class of 1908", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Cloudy and Colder", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - "Crossed Rails", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
    - "Detour", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Drafts, Various, undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - "Feet That Make No Sound", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - "Forgive Me", 1930s (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Fragments, circa 1941 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - "The Ghost Writer", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - "Growing Pains", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - "The Hand", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - "The Human Hat", 1930s (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - "Jeeps May Surprise You" (by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney?), undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - "Julia and Her Ghost,", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - "Kitty's Annabel", circa 1930s (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - "Machine", 1929 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - "Making Mother Happy", 1930s (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930s (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - "Misfit Mary", undated (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - "Mr. Drummond's Client", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - "Mr. Simon's Importance", 1930s (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - "Olive Oil from Palestine" (by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney?), undated (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - "Restless Past", circa 1940 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Sam Goes On", undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "Sawdust and Sunshine", 1930s (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "A Star Beyond", undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Stories for Gallishaw Course (?), circa 1933 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
    - Story Ideas (?), undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "A Thousand Trails", undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Three Brothers and a Madonna", circa 1940 (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
    - "Triple Life", circa 1940 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Untitled (Box 23)
      - ("I had just come back from Paris..."), undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - ("It was a hot Tuesday morning..."), undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - ("Miss Crawford's house was..."), undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - ("Mr. Caruso's latest song intermingled..."), undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - ("The pale saffron towers..."), circa 1910 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - ("Tony was going...") (by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney?), undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - ("It was a little after..."), 1930s (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Synopsis ("An imaginary island in the Mediterranean..."), undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - "The Useless Memorial", undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - "White Voices" by Phyllis Lane (pseudonym of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney), 1974; 1911 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Journals and Notebooks, circa 1901-1940; 7.4
    This subseries consists of journals and notebooks containing Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney's handwritten drafts of stories and autobiographical and other writings, including two stories written under the pseudonym Jane Philliper. Writings in this subseries are often related to (possibly being early drafts of) those found in other subseries.
    Journals and notebooks are partially scanned; duplicates and some draft versions have not been scanned.
    - Autobiographical Writings, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - "The Bridge of Light" (7 vols.), undated (Box 23, Folder 23-26)
    - "A Foreign Enterprise - A Novel", undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - "Intermediate", undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - "Love's Philosophy", circa 1906 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - "Mr. Jinks, the Detective" by Jane Philliper (pseudonym of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney), undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Rosalind - A Story," Vols. I and II, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Sawdust and Sunshine", undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "A Simple Tale", undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Spy Story", 1918 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Story and Poetry Book by Jane Philliper, 1885-1886 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Synopsis of a Novel, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Synopsis of Play about Hero, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - "The Tomb Under the Arc de Triumphe" (play), circa 1940 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "Travels in Foreign Countries and in the Mind", circa 1901 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
    - Unidentified Writings, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Untitled Novel, 1901 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Untitled Play, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Untitled Stories, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - "White Voices", 1911 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments, 1910s-1930s; 7.5
    This subseries consists of drafts and fragments of unidentified writings by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, which may or may not relate to writings in other subseries.
    Series is partially scanned; duplicates and some draft versions have not been scanned.
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments, 1910s-1930s (Box 24, Folder 17-21)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments, 1910s-1930s (Box 25, Folder 1-18)
  - Other Writings, 1889-1940; 7.6
    This subseries consists of writings by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney apart from her more creative writing, including autobiographical and early writings, an essay on the problems of reconstruction in France after the First World War, limericks and poems, notebooks on art and history, her published writings on art (including an article entitled "The 'Useless' Memorial" and a series of articles entitled "The End of America's Apprenticeship in Art" which appeared in Arts and Decoration in 1920), writings on art, and other miscellaneous writings.
    Other writings are partially scanned; duplicates and some draft versions have not been scanned.
    - Autobiographical Writings, "My History", undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Autobiographical Writings, Various, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Early Writings, "A Scene on a Train", 1889 August (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Early Writings, 1889 November (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Early Writings, undated (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
    - "General Problems of Reconstruction in France", circa 1915-1916 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Limericks and Poems, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Writings and Sketches, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1909-1935 (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1910-1940 (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
    - Notebooks, Notes on Art, undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Notebooks, Notes on Egypt, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Notebooks, Notes on European History, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Notebooks, Notes on Italian Art, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Published Writings, 1920 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Writings on Art, circa 1930s (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Writings on Art, undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Writings on Whitney Studio, undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1918; 7.7
    This subseries consists of writings by others, including the galley proof of a memoir by Julien H. Bryan about his time as an ambulance driver during the First World War (published by The Macmillan Company in 1918), a story by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney's collaborator, Ronald Bodley, and stories possibly by other students in the writing course with Whitney. Also found is a signed copy of Between Sittings: An Informal Autobiography of Jo Davidson, in which a signed 1936 watercolor by Davidson is enclosed.
    Series is partially scanned; the bulk of the published manuscripts, Ambulance 464, and Between Sittings: An Informal Autobiography of Jo Davidson, have not been scanned.
    - Ambulance 464 by Julien H. Bryan, circa 1918 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - "The Arrow" by Ronald Bodley, undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Between Sittings: An Informal Autobiography of Jo Davidson (The Dial Press: New York, 1951), 1936 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - "Episode No. 1 - Greece" by Joseph Linden Smith (?), undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - "The Proof of the Evolution of Man From Apes" by Harry Storm, undated (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - "Radiant Fatherhood" by Lincoln Steffens, undated (Box 26, Folder 27)
- Scrapbooks, 1893-1942; Series 8; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 26-27, 33, 35
  This series consists of scrapbooks of clippings, photographs, letters and other material, compiled by Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, Flora Whitney Miller, and possibly others. Scrapbooks document aspects of Whitney's early public life (from 1893 to 1896); Whitney's sculpture commissions and exhibitions; the construction and unveiling of the St. Nazaire and Buffalo Bill memorials, among others; art competitions sponsored by Whitney; exhibitions at the Whitney Studio; the field hospital in Juilly, France; horse racing; the death of Harry Payne Whitney in 1930; and the sickness and death of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney in 1942.
  The bulk of the scrapbooks have been scanned; some enclosed printed material has not been scanned.
  Scrapbooks are arranged in chronological order. More detailed descriptions for certain scrapbooks are provided below.
  - "Gertrude Vanderbilt - Collection of Newspaper Clippings, Letters, etc. etc.", 1893-1896 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Scrapbook (unbound), 1907 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    Includes list of artwork in an exhibition at the Colony Club, 1907 April 9; and clippings on art.
  - Scrapbook (unbound), 1912-1917 (Box 26, Folder 30-32)
    Includes clippings and correspondence relating to Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney's sculptures and commissions (such as the Titanic Memorial and "Fountain of El Dorado" for the Panama-Pacific International Exposition), Whitney Studio, Juilly Field Hospital, and various art exhibitions, sales, and competitions (such as the War Art Competition and the Immigrant in America Prize Contest).
  - Scrapbook (unbound), 1917 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Includes clippings on exhibiton at Whitney Studio, Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, and Macdougal Alley Festa; photographs of an exhibition of Whitney's sculpture at the Palace of Fine Arts, San Francisco; photographs of Whitney; and an unidentified drawing.
  - "Clippings on Exhibition of War Sculpture in Studio and Alley" (unbound), 1919-1920 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "Social Overseas Exhibition / Providence Memorial" (unbound), 1925-1926; 1921-1922 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "Exhibition Abroad / Overseas Exhibition / Announcement of Buffalo Bill Commission / Washington Heights Memorial / Miscellaneous Articles About Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney" (unbound), 1922 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - "St. Nazaire, Clippings" (unbound), 1924-1927 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - "St. Nazaire, Clippings - Snapshots - Construction Unveiling" (unbound), 1924-1926 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - "Buffalo Bill Clippings, vol. 1" (unbound), 1924 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "Buffalo Bill Clippings, vol. 2" (unbound), 1924 (Box 27, Folder 8-9)
  - "Buffalo Bill Clippings and Pictures, vol. 3a" (unbound), 1924 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - "Buffalo Bill Clippings, vol. 3b" (unbound), 1936; 1924 (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
  - Scrapbook, 1927-1929 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    Includes clippings on sculpture commissions (Columbus Memorial, D.A.R. Memorial, and Theodore Roosevelt Memorial in Panama), an exhibition at Whitney Studio Club, and the erection of Titanic Memorial.
  - Scrapbook of Photographs of Horse Racing, 1928-1930 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    Oversized material housed in Box 35
    Includes photographs of races horses at Belmont Park, of horse operations at Brookdale, some of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney and Harry Payne Whitney at races, and of others.
  - Scrapbook of Clippings on Death of Harry Payne Whitney, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - "Selected Press Clippings re: Sickness and Death of Mrs. Harry Payne Whitney" (compiled by Flora Whitney Miller), 1942 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Oversize, "Gertrude Vanderbilt - Collection of Newspaper Clippings, Letters, etc. etc." scanned with Box 26, Folder 28, 1893-1896 (Box 33)
  - Oversize, "St. Nazaire, Clippings" (unbound) scanned with Box 27, Folder 5, 1924-1927 (Box 33)
  - Oversize, "St. Nazaire, Clippings - Snapshots - Construction Unveiling" (unbound) scanned with Box 27, Folder 6, 1924-1926 (Box 33)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook of Photographs of Horse Racing scanned with Box 27, Folder 14, 1928-1930 (Box 35)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook of Clippings on Death of Harry Payne Whitney scanned with Box 27, Folder 15, 1930 (Box 35)
  - Oversize, "Selected Press Clippings re: Sickness and Death of Mrs. Harry Payne Whitney" (compiled by Flora Whitney Miller) scanned with Box 27, Folder 16, 1942 (Box 35)
- Printed Material, 1859-1942; Series 9; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 27-28, 36
  This series consists of clippings, exhibition catalogs, programs, and publications. Included are clippings about the Whitney and Vanderbilt families, Whitney's engagement to Harry Payne Whitney in 1896, Whitney's artistic and philanthropic activities, Flora Payne Whitney's first marriage, Whitney's sculptures, Harry Payne Whitney's death in 1930, the opening of the Whitney Museum of American Art in 1931, the publication of Whitney's novel Walking the Dusk (under the pseudonym L. J. Webb),catalogs include ones for Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney sculpture exhibitions, for exhibitions at the Whitney studio, and for other artists (including Jo Davidson, Andrew O'Connor, and Robert Chanler).
  Printed material is partially scanned; some news clippings have not been scanned and only covers and relevant pages of some publications have been scanned.
  - Clippings, 1859-1890 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    Oversized material housed in Box 36
  - Clippings, 1891-1899 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1902-1916 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1917-1919 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1920-1921 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1923-1926 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1927-1930 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1932-1934 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1935-1936 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1937-1940 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1941-1942 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1943 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Clippings of Sculpture, Portraits, Art-Related (found together as is in notebook), 1924; undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Clippings of Gertrude V. Whitney Sculpture, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Clippings on Walking the Dusk, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements (Box 28)
    - Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney Sculpture Exhibitions, 1916-1942 (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
    - Friends of the Young Artists and Whitney Studio Club Exhibitions, 1916-1928 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Other Artists, 1910-1933 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1916-1925 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Programs, London Theatre, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
  - Programs, Societe d'Architectes des Beaux Artes, 1910 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Publications, 1933; 1909 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Oversize, Clippings scanned with Box 27, Folder 17, 1859-1890 (Box 36)